<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Marcus1car Blog</title>
    <link>https://marcus1car.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Marcus1car Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 19:10:11 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://marcus1car.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes 101 : What It Is, How It Works, and Why It Matters</title>
      <link>https://marcus1car.github.io/posts/k8s_101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 19:10:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marcus1car.github.io/posts/k8s_101/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this second installement in my series of articles, I will cover the  container orchestration  tool &lt;strong&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/strong&gt;.&#xA;Since late 2024, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;strong&gt;Docker&lt;/strong&gt; a lot for my projects. It’s been a game changer, no more dependency errors, broken setups, or messy environments. It just works.&#xA;But once I started looking into real-world use cases for Docker, I saw a lot of mentions of Kubernetes, &lt;strong&gt;K8s&lt;/strong&gt; for short.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-kubernetes-&#34;&gt;What is Kubernetes ?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an open source &lt;strong&gt;container orchestration platform&lt;/strong&gt;. Which means that using it you can run, manage, and scale containerized apps accross clusters of machines. It’s designed for large-scale applications, where managing containers manually with Docker quickly gets messy. You have to worry about starting/stopping containers, restarting them when they crash, assigning ports, managing storage, keeping track of their health, and more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ansible 101 : What It Is, How It Works, and Why It Matters</title>
      <link>https://marcus1car.github.io/posts/ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 14:45:36 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marcus1car.github.io/posts/ansible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently started digging more into Infrastructure as Code  (&lt;em&gt;IaC&lt;/em&gt;) tools and &lt;em&gt;Devops&lt;/em&gt; tools in general to gain skills and knowledge for my future internship. In this series of articles, I will go over multiple tools and topics. We will mainly cover the basics, concepts, and provide simple examples. If I end up doing a lab with a specific tool, I will publish an article for it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here we will cover one of the most popular IaC tools out there, &lt;strong&gt;Ansible&lt;/strong&gt;. We will look at how it works, and where it fits in the world of IT automation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure-Docker-Container 1 : Building a Secure Analysis Environment</title>
      <link>https://marcus1car.github.io/posts/securedockercontainer_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 16:35:43 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marcus1car.github.io/posts/securedockercontainer_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-my-docker-security-project&#34;&gt;Introduction to My Docker Security Project&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As my first independent project ,&#xA;I aim to create a secure, isolated environment for file analysis and execution.&#xA;This series of blog posts will chronicle the development of my Secure Docker Container, offering insights into Docker,&#xA;cybersecurity principles, and practical software development.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why this project?&lt;/strong&gt; In cybersecurity, safely analyzing potentially harmful files is crucial.&#xA;A secure, controlled environment helps professionals examine files without risking their main system.&#xA;This blog series will document my journey, mistakes, lessons, and successes included.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
